Fannie Lee Leverette scrapbooks, circa 1900-1948
Emory University
Fannie Lee Leverette scrapbooks,circa 1900-1948
Leverette, Fannie Lee.
Manuscript Collection No.135
1 microfilm reel (MF)
Microfilm copy of four scrapbooks kept by Georgia public school teacher and journalist Fannie Lee Leverette which include letters, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia documenting Miss Leverette's personal life and professional career.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Loaned for reproduction, 1978.
Restrictions on Access
Unrestricted access.
Biographical Note
Fannie Lee Leverette (circa 1869-1956), a public school teacher and journalist, was born in Eatonton, Putnam County, Georgia. Leverette was the daughter of Frank Leverette and Mary Ella Wyatt Leverette. She was educated in the public schools of Eatonton and at Wesleyan College, and taught in the public schools of Eatonton (circa l904-1914), Social Circle (circa 1915-circa 1924), and Thomson (circa 1925-circa 1940). She also served as assistant editor of the Eatonton Messenger and as Eatonton correspondent for the Macon Telegraph, the Atlanta Journal, the Savannah Morning News, and the Augusta Chronicle.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of a microfilm copy of four scrapbooks kept by Fannie Lee Leverette from 1900-1948. The scrapbooks include letters, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia documenting Miss Leverette's personal life and professional career. Major portions of the scrapbooks relate to Eatonton, Miss Leverette's home, and to Thomson and Social Circle. Included are letters, articles, and photographs relating to the family of Joel Chandler Harris, of Eatonton houses and people, and articles by Miss Leverette about the history of Eatonton.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Collins, M.D.; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976.; Harris family.; Harris, Joel Chandler, 1848-1908.; Leverette family.; Vinson, Carl, 1883-1981.
Topical Terms
African Americans--Georgia--Eatonton.; American newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.; Education--Georgia.; Plantations--Georgia.; Women journalists--Georgia.
Geographic Names
Augusta (Ga.).; Eatonton (Ga.); Social Circle (Ga.); Thomson (Ga.); West (U.S.)--Description and travel.
Form/Genre Terms
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
Occupation
Educator.; Journalist.
Container List
- Scrapbook 1
- Photo and clippings re Fannie Lee Leverette (page 2) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Photos of people and places in Eatonton (page 5) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Poems, photos (page 7-8) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- FLL's "biography" (page 10) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Information about Eatonton, friends, and family (pages 11-13) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Postcards and notes re Joel Chandler Harris and family (pages 15-16) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Letters and articles re Gov. John M. Slaton (page 17) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- FLL articles re Eatonton (pages 23-25) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Articles re Eatonton (pages 27-29) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Eatonton (pages 31-32) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Western trip (pages 33-36) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- FLL newspaper articles (pages 37-38) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Photos and notes re Social Circle, Ga. (page 40) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Postcard views of Eatonton (page 44) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Family photos (pages 49-53) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Letter from Joel Chandler Harris, Jr. (December 6, 1948) (insert) (page 54) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Leverette article re William H. Seward's connection with Putnam County (page 56) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Leverette article on Joel Chandler Harris's mother (page 60) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Photos, etc. re Turnwold and JCH (pages 61-66) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Letter of JCH to FLL, April 15, 1901 (page 63) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Letter of "Essie" LaRose Harris, August 4, 1918 (page 64) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Article and 3 letters of Esther LaRose Harris (page 65) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Georgia's historic highways (page 71) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Georgia Press trip (pages 76-79) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Unveiling of monument to Uncle Remus in Eatonton; article of death of FLL's mother (page 81) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Personal and family photos, history, and genealogy (page 83-) (Box MF1, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook 2
- Postcards and clippings re history of Georgia and the Confederacy (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Letter, March 24, 1930, from Evelyn Harris (page 7) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Two notes (1918 and 1922) from Esther LaRose Harris (pages 7-8) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Photos and postcards from FLL's Texas trip with article by FLL on Mirabeau Lamar (page 10) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- "Around and About Atlanta" by FLL (page 30) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- "A Woman's View of the World of Politics" by FLL (page 31) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Article on Georgia plantation "Hilltops" by FLL (page 33) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Article (by Susan Myrick) about James 0. Cooper, Conductor on the Central of Georgia Railroad between Eatonton and Macon for 45 years (page 40) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- "Some Remembrances of Judge John M. Dooly, An Early Georgian," by FLL (page 46) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Article on William H. Crawford, by FLL (page 48) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Articles on Putnam County history (pages 51-57) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Article on George M. Troup; note (June 22, 1914) from M. L. Brittain (page 60) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- "Oldest Road in Georgia" (page 64) (Box MF1, Folder 2)
- Scrapbook 3 (Pages not numbered; mainly FLL's teaching career in Thomson, Ga.)
- Family photographs, poems (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Two letters of M. D. Collins, State superintendent of schools, July 8 and September 9, 1940 (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Clippings about and letter (May 22, 1940) from Congressman Cal Vinson (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Letter from James A. Farley, November 23, 1940 (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Letter from Lucien Harris, December 1, 1948 (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Letter from James A. Farley, December 27, 1940, and autographed photo (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Letter from Julian LaRose Harris, December 6, 1948 (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photograph of Captain John S. Reid of Eatonton (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Letter from James M. Cox, January 20, 1941 (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Family and personal photographs (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photographs of students from Thomson (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photographs of black servants (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photographs of Thomson, Ga. (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photograph and story re Leverette home in Eatonton (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Reminiscences of "Grandma Mary" Harris (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- "Mental Album" of FLL (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- FLL's genealogy (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Record of "family tragedies", including deaths of several family members at hands of their servants (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photographs of Eatonton and Thomson (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photographs re Thomas E. Watson (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photos re T. C. Martie of Thomson (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Photos of Augusta (Box MF1, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook 4 (Pages not numbered)
- Clippings by and about FLL (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Christmas and greeting cards (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of Maggie Adam Harvey, mother of Leland Harvey, photo and article re Margery Harris Leonard Barber (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Letters from President Woodrow Wilson (November 14, 1912), Governor John M. Slaton (September 15, 1913), Sarah Grant Slaton, (February 6, 1914), and Esther LaRose Harris (July 27, 1889) (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of Rock Eagle Park near Eatonton (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of parents and home in Eatonton, and letter (November 20, 1935) from Martha Berry (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of students, Cousin Frances Hearn, and servant, and letter from W. P. Collins (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Testimonials re teaching of Fannie Lee Leverette (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos and cards from her students, photos of Thomson schools (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Family and personal photos (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of Eatonton and Thomson and Social Circle (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of the Knox Hotel in Thomson (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of Eatonton, family, friends, black servants (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photo of Eatonton group with airplane, "The Butterfly," in 1911 (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of Thomson (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Photos of "Hickory Hill" (Box MF1, Folder 4)
- Letters from Carl Vinson (Box MF1, Folder 4)